I'm sorry about Kirschblüte.
Here's the real pig
that lives outside the Gran Mur!
June 13th,  Stellar Year 2148
That's not funny, Haruto.
Looks like that didn't go over well.
You're supposed to laugh.
I don't think that was in the cards.
Where's Anju, anyway?
I need her to take my turn making dinner.
She's on cleaning duty today.
You would know, huh, Daiya?
All the other girls went, too.
When was this?
Right after breakfast, I think.
It's lunchtime.
Yeah, it shouldn't take that long.
So they're bathing.
And right now, the river is...
Heaven on earth!
No, no! Absolutely not!
Don't be such a stick in the mud!
We might die tomorrow!
You say that all the time, Haruto!
Got it. We won't look at Anju.
No, you'll definitely see her!
And that's not the issue.
I'm not going!
Absolutely not!
Before we're each men and women,
we're all staunch comrades!
Staunch comrades!
It's so cold!
It feels so good!
Kaie, what are you doing?
Stop sitting there and join in the fun!
I don't know. I think I can
look sexy just fine over here.
What are you talking about?
You could look at this place as heaven.
Just join in the fun!
That's right!
Is it okay for us to be
out here having fun, anyway?
You're so serious sometimes, Kaie.
It's fine.
We cleaned up like we were supposed to.
And Shin knew we would do this
when he gave the okay, right?
Our captain does understand that,
even if he never changes expression.
Sorry, I should've realized!
Both you and Shin don't have any duties today,
so we should've given you
an excuse to be alone!
No!
It's not like that!
What do you like about that guy?
I can never tell what he's thinking.
I said it's not like that!
What about you, Kaie?
Shin? He's not bad, I guess.
He's the silent type. Stoic. I like that.
W-Wait! Kaie!
I see. I see!
If nobody else is interested,
I can go after him myself, right?
Maybe I'll try some traditional
Eastern "yobai" tonight...
K-Kaie!
Um, well... I don't really care
about Shin in the slightest, but...
I don't think that's right.
You know, an Eastern lady
should be dignified and reserved, so...
You're so cute, Kurena!
Stop it!
How many times do I have to tell you guys?
This isn't okay!
You're staring more than we are, Daiya.
Why are you here, again?
To keep an eye on you two!
Multiple targets... Ready!
Fire!
Are you insane?
Ow!
Hey... wait. Oh, no!
Daiya...
You will be missed.
Die!
You pervert!
Stay out there!
So...
What is it, Daiya?
You can say, "Are you okay?"
in a cute voice, you know, Anju.
Oh, my. Are you okay, Daiya?
The rest of you need to show yourselves, too!
Ow!
Theo!
So, what do you want?
Well, um... you know.
Right, Haruto?
Right, Daiya?
Me?
Um, well...
You know.
There was something we wanted to ask you.
Why didn't you just use your Para-RAID?
Well, we wouldn't want to interrupt the fun
you girls were having, right?
It'd be awkward if you were
talking about romance, right?
For example, if Kurena
were saying, "I love Shin!"
She was just saying that.
I know!
Let's have her say that
right before we think Shin will connect!
I can't wait to see the reaction!
Kurena's reaction, you mean.
You can't expect anything from Shin.
That Reaper won't even raise an eyebrow.
He's no fun at all!
I did not say that!
Stop it, guys!
You're so cute, Kurena!
So, what did you want to ask us?
Well...
Daiya?
Me again?
Well... um...
What is "yobai"?
I'm not telling you!
I said sorry!
We need to retrieve the clean clothes.
Where's Daiya?
Over there!
Daiya!
Hey Daiya, will you carry the wash for me?
Will you?
Um, is something wrong?
There was a rat. That's all.
A rat?
You can try harder than that.
There are rats?
There are.
Kurena...
Why does he talk
with that woman every night?
He should be spending that time
with the rest of us.
We might die tomorrow!
It's just for now.
The princess will stop calling eventually.
They're both just killing time.
But why even bother being nice
to a white pig?
Shin should just break her already.
Shin doesn't want to break any of them.
And could you tell that to Shin?
You don't like her,
so you want him to break her?
Could you say that to him?
I'm sorry.
But I still hate her.
Those white pigs killed my mom and dad.
They used them as target practice, like garbage.
All white pigs are scum.
I'll never forgive any of them.
Really, Kirschblüte?
Yeah. All these stars came falling down
from the sky like rain.
There were streaks of light
across the whole sky.
It was amazing.
There were really that many shooting stars?
Yes, I couldn't count them all.
A meteor shower?
I've seen one of those, too.
Really?
Yeah, but it was in the middle of a battlefield,
where both my side and the enemy were annihilated,
and there was only a single man beside me.
Right, Undertaker?
Well, that's not very romantic.
And to top it off,
our Juggernauts all ran out of gas.
Until Fido came back
from wherever he went and found us,
we couldn't even move.
Fido?
Our dog.
You have a dog, too?
It's a very unusual dog.
It doesn't go, "woof." It goes, "beep.""
"Beep"?
Nights on the battlefield
are so dark that it's scary.
And then these pale, silent lights began to fall
from the sky, one after another.
I remember I said something weird then,
and it was the biggest mistake of my life.
What did you say, show-off?
I'm not telling.
If the—
"If the last thing I see is this,"
"then maybe that's not so bad."
Why did you have to tell her? Sheesh.
He just snorted!
I doubt we'll ever see something
like that again.
I wish I could've seen
that meteor shower, too...
You couldn't see it where you are?
The lights in town don't shut off at night.
You can't really see the stars here.
You're right, now that I think about it.
Nights here are really dark.
There aren't a lot of people here,
and we're far from everything.
And we shut off all the lights
when we sleep.
So the stars are usually out.
That's one of the good things
about this life, definitely.
One of the good things?
Yes.
Kirschblüte, do you hate us?
Well...
Of course, it hurts being discriminated against,
and it makes me mad.
Life in the camps was hard.
And I'll always be scared when I fight.
So as for the people who forced this on us,
and say it was okay since the Eighty-Six
are livestock and not human...
I can't bring myself to like them.
But...
But I know that not all you Alba are bad.
Just like how not all Eighty-Six are good.
I was one of the rarer races
among the Eighty-Six.
A lot of stuff happened at the camps,
and in my previous units.
Of course, I wasn't the only one
who experienced that.
I'm sure that there are good Alba, too.
Not that I've ever met any.
But a few of my comrades have met them.
So I understand that.
So I won't hate you
just because you're an Alba.
I see.
I need to thank them, then.
Handler One.
I'm taking a bit of an interest in you.
Really?
Can I ask you something, then?
Yes, go ahead.
June 13th, Stellar Year 2148
Why am I doing this, Lena?
I bought you lunch, right?
You'd better buy dinner as well,
or it's not worth it.
What do you need a map for, anyway?
I want to send it to them.
They're fighting without any good maps.
You're bragging about them again?
Well, they're amazing.
They've been in more battles
than the other units
in the past two weeks,
and they still have zero casualties.
Yeah, amazing. Amazing.
But would it kill you to tell me
about a guy who I can actually see?
I'm having an awful time.
This new potential marriage partner...
Theobald?
How long ago was that guy?
Humbert!
His forehead goes up to here.
And he just won't give up.
I made a huge mistake giving him
that handkerchief when we met.
He was sweaty all the way up to here.
It bothers you, right?
Yes, it does.
How do they know
when the Legion are going to attack?
She's not listening at all.
It really is a mystery.
They're always ready to fight
before the enemy even shows up.
Lena, don't get involved any deeper.
They're Eighty-Six.
Don't worry.
We're all humans.
We have a relationship of trust.
What?
Are you okay?
I trust you, Major Milizé.
Here!
You found one!
You owe me dinner.
Thank you!
Now I can help them again.
You can't even see it.
Para-RAID, activate.
Synchronization target: Spearhead Processor.
Thank you all for your work today.
Thank you, Handler One.
Hey there.
Thanks for your call, as always.
Undertaker. First, the arrival date for the resupply
you requested the other day...
I'm sorry, but it's going
to take a little while longer.
Is that a cat?
Yeah. We keep it at the barracks.
I'm the one who found it, by the way.
Right after I got here,
it was crying in front of a house
that'd been blown away by a tank round.
Its parents and siblings got flattened,
but it was just fine.
And for some reason, it's taken more of a liking
to Undertaker than anyone.
He doesn't play with it at all.
It rubs up against him all the time,
and he just pats it once in a while.
I think it's more like
it thinks he's a good bed.
I mean... Just look at it right now.
Yeah, it doesn't move when he's reading.
It'll never get along with
Black Dog, though. He's annoying.
That's mean! And not fair!
I demand you take that back!
Boo! Boo!
What's its name?
Blackie.
Whitey.
Two-Tone.
Kitty.
Shrimp.
Remarque.
Don't name it after the author of
whatever book you're reading now.
And what are you even reading?
You have such bad taste.
Um...
Are there are a lot of them?
Were you listening?
There's just one.
It's a black cat with white paws.
So it's called Blackie
or Whitey or Two-Tone.
It doesn't really have a particular name.
Everybody just calls it whatever
they feel like at the moment.
Lately, it's started coming whenever
you look at it and say something.
I see.
But why?
Um, is something wrong?
There was a rat. That's all.
A rat?
You have a dog, too?
It's a very unusual dog.
I wish I could've seen
that meteor shower, too...
You couldn't see it where you are?
I need to thank them, then.
Handler One.
I'm taking a bit of an interest in you.
Really?
Can I ask you something, then?
Yes, go ahead.
Why do you care about us so much?
Well...
A long time ago, I was saved
on the battlefield by a Processor.
He said to me,
"We are members of the Republic.
We were born here and grew up here."
"It's a citizen's duty to protect his country.
I'm proud to do it."
"That's why we fight."
I think we need to live up
to the example set by his words.
We ask you to fight,
but don't even watch you do it.
We don't try to know you.
That goes against what he said.
And it's terrible.
Handler One.
You're a virgin, aren't you?
Sorry, I didn't mean to say that!
I meant, "like a virgin"?
That's not any better!
I mean, um... like a young girl who thinks
the whole world is made of fields of flowers...
Like you have an untarnished, pure ideal.
Um...
What I wanted to say is...
You're not a bad person.
So I'm going to warn you.
You aren't cut out for that job.
And you shouldn't get involved with us.
We're not fighting
for noble reasons like those.
So there's no need for you to talk to us.
You should get someone else
to take your place before you regret it.
June 15th, Stellar Year 2148
Handler One to all units.
Enemy sighted on radar.
Enemy size is...
We're aware, Handler One.
We are prepared to engage at point 478.
Roger that, Undertaker.
Undertaker, Gunslinger in position.
Laughing Fox to Undertaker.
Third Platoon in position.
Undertaker, please move Gunslinger 500
from her present position. Direction 2 o'clock.
You can't see it where you are,
but there's high ground there.
You can use the hill to provide cover,
and you'll have a wider view.
Confirming.
Gunslinger, can you see the point
from where you are?
Hang on.
Yeah, it's there.
I'll go.
You'll be in the opposite position
from the First Platoon, your main attackers.
When you move from the suppressive fire
phase to defeat in detail,
it should help camouflage your main unit's position
at the start of the battle.
A decoy, basically.
You've got a voice like a little princess,
but that's pretty impressive.
Löwes can't fire at an elevated angle.
They can't bombard her directly
while she's there,
and when she shifts bombardment positions—
Don't get the wrong idea.
It's not a bad idea.
Right, Gunslinger?
I'll do anything, if it'll help the rest of us.
Did you find a new map?
That's helpful.
Should I send it later?
Is that okay? Sending classified information
such as a map to Eighty-Six.
I don't care.
What good is information
if you don't use it?
You think so, huh?
And you're not Eighty-Six.
At least, I've never called you—
Right, right.
Here they come.
Target down.
Fourth Platoon is moving.
What's that Löwe doing there?
Leukosia. I'll hit it from the left.
Back me up.
Roger, Kirschblüte.
Not that way! Kirschblüte!
Wetlands? Here?
I can't move.
No. I don't want to die.
Mission complete.
Good work, everyone.
I'm sorry about Kirschblüte.
If I'd only found the map sooner...
If I'd only done a better job...
"Sorry"? Sorry about what?
From your perspective,
the deaths of a few Eighty-Six
are things you can forget
by the time you go home for dinner.
Sure, we don't have much to do here,
so when nothing's going on,
we can play along with this act where you say,
"I don't discriminate even if other people do.
I don't treat you as pigs."
But we just lost one of our comrades.
Understand that we don't have time
to deal with your hypocrisy now.
Hypocrisy?
Or what, did you think we don't care
when one of our own dies?
Yeah, maybe you're right!
After all, we're not
high-minded humans like you.
We're pigs, less than human!
N-No! I didn't—
Don't try to deny it!
You throw us out here on the battlefield
and treat us like weapons,
while you get to watch from your
warm and safe place inside the walls,
and it doesn't bother you at all!
If that's not treating us
like pigs, what is?
You've never called us "Eighty-Six."
But all that means is you've left it unsaid.
Do you think we're out here fighting
because we want to?
You locked us out here! Forced us to fight!
You've caused the deaths of millions
over the last nine years!
And you do nothing to stop it.
You think that if you just act nice
and talk to us every day,
that counts as treating us
as human, don't you?
You've never even asked us
for our real names!
"Real Name."